Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Information Files, 1879-present CTC.Infofiles.Pgh
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- M
  - Minutellos, 1981
  - Mission Playhouse, 1954
  - Mr. B's Restaurant, 1974-1976
  - Modern Renaissance Theatre, 1982
  - Monahan, Kaspar, 1963-1983
  - Monroeville Arts Council, 1985-1987
  - Monroeville Civic Theatre - SEE MCT Valley Playhouse, 1973-1978
  - Montley, Patricia, 1990
  - Morphic Resonance Ensemble, 1990
  - Morris Kaufman Auditorium - SEE Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association
  - Motion Pictures - Local Productions - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Film Bureau, 1989-2009
  - Mottola, Greg, 2007-2009
  - Mt. Lebanon Parks and Recreation Dept., 1978
  - Mount Lebanon Players, 1956-1975
  - Mount Lebanon Summer Theatre, 1977-1979
  - Mount Mercy College - SEE Carlow College
  - Moving Target Theatre, 1988-1990
  - Murrysville Musical Theatre, 1975
  - Muryo Dance Company, 1990
  - Muses, The, 1976-1987
  - Music for Mt. Lebanon, 1979
  - Music Guild of Pittsburgh, 1961-1963
  - Musical Theatre Guild of Butler, 1969-current
  - Mustin, Burt, 1942-1979
  - Myers, Larry - SEE Coffee with Kurt Cobain, 1995
  - Mystery Lovers Bookshop, 1994
- N
  - Nagle, James (Kimo) - SEE Clowns
  - Names Project Pittsburgh, 1989
  - NAMO Productions, 1992
  - Nathan Group, 1989-1991
  - National Film Registry, 1989
  - National Performing Arts Convention, 2004
  - National Society of Arts and Letters - Pittsburgh Chapter, 1979
  - National Theatre of the Deaf, 1993
  - Negri, Joe - SEE ALSO Beck's Patio Theater, 1989
  - Nemacolin, 1991
  - Nemetz, Lenora, 1975-current
  - Nesbitt, Evelyn, 1977-2008
  - New Castle Playhouse, 1975-1999
  - New Europe Arts Festival, 1993
  - New Kensington Civic Theatre, 1960-1993
  - New Kensington Civic Theatre, 1976-1998
  - New Nixon Theatre, 1974-1976
  - New Pittsburgh Playwright's Marathon, 1990
  - New Theatre, 1937
  - New York Theatre Co., 1974
  - Newman Players, 1930
  - Nickelodeon - SEE Harris Theatres, Davis, Harry, Harris, John H., and John P., 1907-2005
  - Nicotero, Greg, 1990-current
  - Nixon Theatre, 1930-current
  - Norris, Jan
  - North Hills Performing Arts, 1974-1988
  - North Star Players, 1974-1986
  - Northern Theatre Guild, 1981
  - Nunn, Bill, 1989-2016
- O
  - Off-Forbes Festival of Performance Art, 1985
  - Off the Wall productions, 2011-current
  - Oglebay Institute, 1970-1989
  - Ohio River Valley Project, 1979
  - Old Economy, 1981
  - Olde Trail Players, 1976
  - Olympic Studio of Dancing, 1928-1930
  - Olympic Theater
  - Omaha Magic Theatre, 1988
  - O'Malley, Bingo, 1983-2009
  - On Cue Productions
  - On My Own Creations, 1984
  - Ondine, 1985
  - Open-air-theatre, 1978-1980
  - Opera Co. of Philadelphia
  - Opera House - New Castle, 1913
  - Opera House - Pittsburgh
  - Opera House - Waynesburg, 1986
  - Opera Workshop, 1974-1976
  - O'Ross, Ed, 1988
  - O'Steen, Michael and Michelle, 1989-1990
  - Our Gang Production Company
  - Our Town's Musical Theatre, 1982
- P
  - PACE Theatrical Group, 1990
  - Page, Jean, 1990
  - Pageants - SEE Festivals, Celebrations, pageants, etc.
  - Palace Theater, 1979-2002
  - Palmer, Maree Gray
  - Parker, Stuart, 1987
  - Paris, Barry, 1989-1990
  - Park Players - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Department of Parks and Recreation, 1975-1980
  - Parks, Van Dyke, 1989
  - Parry, Florence Fischer, 1942
  - Patina Productions, 1986-1989
  - Pavarotti, Luciano, 1990-2007
  - Pearl Theatre
  - Pennsylvania Composers Conference, 1989
  - Penn Hills Players - SEE ALSO Characters East, 1971-1986
  - Penn State Players New Kensington Campus - SEE Pennsylvania State University, New Kensington
  - Penn Theatre, 1971-current
  - Penn Wood Players, 1982
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 1981-1990
  - Pennsylvania Dance Theater, 1989-1990
  - Pennsylvania Repertory Theatre - SEE ALSO Lion Walk, 1975-1978
  - Pennsylvania State University Beaver campus, 1978-1985
  - Pennsylvania State University New Kensington - SEE Penn State Players, New Kensington, 1970-1993
  - Penny, Rob, 1988-2004
  - People Place of Pittsburgh, 1979
  - Peppard, George, 1975-1980
  - Perfect Circle Theatre, 1986
  - Performance Art - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Mattress Factory, The Artery, Three Rivers Arts Festival, 1989-1991
  - Performing Arts Theater, 1981-1984
  - Performers North, 1985
  - Perry Theater, 1990
  - Pershing Theatre, 1920
  - Perspective Theatre
  - Peters Township Thespian Troupe, 1974-1976
  - Petrov, Nicolas, 1990-current
  - Phantom of the Opera - Ken Hill, 1989-1991
  - Phantom of the Opera - Andrew Lloyd Webber, 1989
  - Physical Theatre Project - SEE ALSO Cousin, Tome, 1989-1991
  - Picerno, Paul, 1952
  - Pied Piper Players of North Hills, 1982
  - Pinsker, Allan, 2013
  - Pitt Theatre, 1963
  - Pittsburgh (2006 film) - SEE ALSO Goldblum, Jeff
  - Pittsburgh Academy of Medicine - SEE Allegheny County Medical Society, Hospitals, Academy Players, 1974-1983
  - Pittsburgh Alliance of Composers, 1990
  - Pittsburgh Allegheny County Cultural Alliance - SEE ALSO Tix Booth, 1984-1988
  - Pittsburgh Arts Advocacy Council, 1986-1989
  - Pittsburgh Athletic Association, 1912
  - Pittsburgh Bicentennial - SEE ALSO United States Bicentennial 1976 (in Pennsylvania), Festivals etc., 1958-1959
  - Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble - SEE ALSO Theatre Urge, 1976-1991
  - Pittsburgh Broadway Series, 1998-2007
  - Pittsburgh Center for the Arts, 1981-1995
  - Pittsburgh Children's Theatre, 1941-1946
  - Pittsburgh Children's Museum, 1988-1992
  - Pittsburgh Children's Theatre, 1944-1946
  - Pittsburgh Civic Playhouse Programs, 1934
  - Pittsburgh Comedy Alliance - SEE Comedy Clubs
  - Pittsburgh Comedy Club - SEE Zito and Bean
  - Pittsburgh Cultural Trust - SEE Zito and Bean, 1987-current
  - Pittsburgh Dance Alloy, 1989-1991
  - Pittsburgh Deaf Theatre, 1984
  - Pittsburgh Department of Parks and Recreation - SEE ALSO Park Players, Puppets, 1978-1980
  - Pittsburgh Film Bureau - SEE ALSO Motion Pictures - Local Productions, Pittsburgh Film Office, 1989-1995
  - Pittsburgh Filmmakers, 1989-2003
  - Pittsburgh Film Office - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Film Bureau, 2000-2003
  - Pittsburgh History and Landmarks Foundation, 1976
  - Pittsburgh International Children's Theater, 2000-2008
  - Pittsburgh International Folk Theatre, 1989
  - Pittsburgh Mime Theatre, 1983-1986
  - Pittsburgh Musical Institute Inc., 1938
  - Pittsburgh Opera Center, 1989-2001
  - Pittsburgh Oratoria Society, 1990
  - Pittsburgh Performing Arts Foundation, 1967-1968
  - Pittsburgh Opera House - SEE Warner Center, Pittsburgh Theatre Programs
  - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1990-2008
  - Pittsburgh Playwrights - SEE Playwrights, 1984-1986
  - Pittsburgh Playwright's Festival, 1985-1988
  - Pittsburgh Poetry Exchange, 1982
  - Pittsburgh Pride Theater Festival, 2004-2005
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1998
    This folder primarily contains clippings on the planning and construction of the O'Reilly Theater
  - Pittsburgh Puppet Theatre - SEE Puppets
  - Pittsburgh Queer Theatre - SEE ALSO Gay and Lesbian theatre, 1993-1995
  - Pittsburgh Renaissance Theatre, 1982
  - Pittsburgh Repertory Theatre - SEE Pittsburgh Renaissance Theatre
  - Pittsburgh Summer Playhouse, 1933
  - Pittsburgh Theatre. (old Drury) - SEE Third Street Theatre
  - Pittsburgh Theatre Laboratories, 1993-1994
  - Pittsburgh White Barn Theatre, 1963
  - la Place - SEE ALSO Gorman Lone Productions, 1993
  - Play it Again Theatre Company, 1980-1981
  - Playhouse, The (Young Men's Hebrew Association) - SEE YM and WHA
  - Playworks, 1985
  - Playwrights - SEE Pittsburgh Playwrights
  - Playwrights Laboratory Theatre
  - Playwright's Workshop of Pittsburgh, 1990-1991
  - Plaza, 1988
  - Pleasant Valley Playhouse, 1979
  - Podesta, Rossand, 1955
  - Pohl, Jude, 1989-1997
  - Portable Theatre Company, 1986
  - Porter, Billy, 1990-current
  - Portfolio - SEE ALSO Miller, Dennis, and Zito and Bean, 1980-1981
  - Posvar, Mildred, 1987-current
  - Powell, Catherine, 1976-1977
  - Powell, Dick, 1985
  - Powell, William, 1930-1984
  - Premiere Productions - SEE ALSO Coll, Jason, 1991
  - Premieres in Pittsburgh - SEE ALSO Motion Pictures-Local Productions, 1990-1991
  - Presbyterian Hospital - Cotton Carnival, 1944
  - Primary Stages, 1993
  - Prison Theater, 1974
  - Pro Arts Guide, 1999
  - Productions W.
  - Promethea Theatre Company, 2000-2007
  - Promoters of Arts - SEE Black Theatre, 1990
  - Prospect Alumni, 1946
  - Prunczik, Karen, 1980-1990
  - P.T. Barnum's Greatest Show on Earth and Great London Circus, circa 1890
  - Puppets - SEE Lovelace, Pittsburgh Department of Parks and Recreation, Marionette Theatre Arts Council, Flying Dragon Puppet Theatre, Caravan, Pittsburgh Puppet Theatre, Marionettes, Performing Arts for Children, 55th Marionette Company, 1980-2002
  - Puppet Connection - SEE Puppets
  - Puppet Theatre of the Unicorn, The - SEE Puppets
  - Purgatory, 1981
  - Pyramid Productions, 1991-1995
  - Pyramid Ten Minute Marathon, 1991
  - Pytka, Joe, 1989
- R
  - Raab, Ellis
  - Rage of the Stage Players, 2003-2009
  - Rak, Rachelle, 1988-1990
  - Rainer, Iris, 1980
  - Raphael, Margaret, 1989
  - Rauh Family - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1978-current
  - Rawson, Christopher, 1982-current
  - Red Barn Players - SEE ALSO Silver Fox Playhouse, 1978-2003
    Please note that this is the Red Barn Theater of Ellwood City, PA.
  - Redwood, John Henry, 1991-1993
  - Rendina, Maria, 1989-1991
  - Reed, Vivian, 1976-1978
  - Regent, The, 1915-2002
  - Renaissance and Baroque Society, 1989-2006
  - Rendina, Maria, 1989-1991
  - Repertory Players
  - Retired Senior Volunteer Program Theatre Guild, 1976
  - Rex Theater, 1989-1991
  - Reynolds, J.A., 1994-1995
  - Ribet Productions, 1976
  - Ribman, Ronald, 1983
  - Richard Rodgers Award, 2002
  - Ridge Avenue Theatre - SEE Community College of Allegheny County
  - Ridge Road Children's Theatre, 1974
  - Robocop, 1986
  - Rodef Shalom, 2001-2002
  - Rogers Company, 1982
  - Rogers, Fred, 1987-2003
  - Rogers School for the Creative and Performing Arts, 1981-1992
  - Romero, George, 1987-2002
  - Rooney, Tom, 1990
  - Rose, Hugh Alexander, 1990
  - Rosebud, 1993
  - Row, Arthur, 2003
  - Rowland and Clark Theatres, 1991
  - Roxian Theater, 1994
  - Royall, Julia, 1976
  - RSVP Theatre Guild - SEE Retired Senior Volunteer Program Theatre Guild
  - Ruoti, Helena, 1983-current
  - Russell, Barbara, 1998
  - Russell, Lilian, 1936-current
- S
  - Saint Francis College, 1974-1981
  - Saltworks - SEE Christian Arts Company
  - Salvation Army - Shady Avenue, 1932
  - Sam S. Schubert Theatre, 1921
  - San Francisco Mime Troupe, 1986
  - San Giacomo, Laura, 1988-1990
  - Sankowich, Lee, 1989
  - Savini, Tom - SEE ALSO Motion Pictures-Local, 1990
  - Savoy and Brennan (Bert Savoy and Jay Brennan), 1918-1925
  - Sawmill Theatre, 1984-1987
  - Schenley High School, 1989
  - Schenley Theatre, 1914-1923
  - Schmidt, William, 1990
  - Schoolhouse Arts Center
  - Schoolhouse Theatre at Roslyn Farms Community Center, 1978
  - Schooltime Theatre, 1980-1990
  - Schwantner, Joseph, 1989
  - Schwartz, Stephen, 1976
  - 2nd Stage, 1992
  - Sellars, Peter, 1973-1984
  - Selma Burke Art Center, 1971-1982
  - Semi-Serious Acting Co. - SEE ALSO Bicsey, Jon
  - Senator Theatre - SEE ALSO Nixon Theatre, 1941
  - Seton Hill College, 1975-1992
  - Sewickley Academy
  - Sewickley Valley Players, 1984-1985
  - Shaliko Company
  - Shakespeare in Pittsburgh, 1980-2000
  - Shakespeare Club, 1881
  - Shaktman, Ben
  - Shange, Ntozake, 1991
  - Shapiro, Mel, 1990-1991
  - Sharp, George - SEE George Sharp Players
  - Sheraton Lakeview Resort, 1987-1988
  - Sheraton North, 1983
  - Sheridan Square, 1914-2005
  - Sieff, Eileen, 1990
  - Silence of the Lambs - SEE ALSO Foster, Jodie and Motion Pictures-Local, 1990
  - Singleton, Margeaux, 1990
  - Silent Comedy Theatre, The, 1981
  - Silver Fox Playhouse, 1975-1982
  - Silver Trumpet Productions, 1985
  - Skinner, Edith, 2009
  - Sleasman, David J., 1989
  - Slippery Rock College, 1979-2004
  - Smith, Tom, Father, 1983-1986
  - Soldiers and Sailors Memorial Hall, 1968-current
  - Somerset Playhouse, 1979
  - Sothern, E.H., 1929
  - South Allegheny Community Theatre, 1975-1983
  - South Hill Performing Arts, 1978-1979
  - South Hills Theatre, 1985-1988
  - South Oakland Arts Council, Inc., 1971-1975
  - South Park Playhouse, 1938
  - South Park Summer Concert Series, 1990
  - South Park Summer Theatre
  - South Park Theatre, 1938-1999
  - Southers, Mark, 2004-current
  - Stackhouse Park, 1994
  - Stag, Danny, 1989
  - Stagehands, 1990
  - Stage Left, 1980
  - Stage and Play Society, 1931-1935
  - Stage Right! - Greensburg, 2001
  - Stage Right - SEE ALSO Fox Chapel Community Players, 1983-current
  - Stageworks Theatre Company, 1982
  - Stage 62, 1976-1987
  - Stanley Theatre, 1980-current
  - Star Lake Amphitheatre, 1989-1990
  - Starr, Sally, 1926-1958
  - State Music Players, 1984-1985
  - State Theatre, 1991
  - Steeltown Entertainment Project, 2003-current
  - Stewart, James, 1974-1997
  - Stewart, Maggie, 1989
  - Stock, David, 1989-1990
  - Stohl, Hank
  - Stone House Players, 1941
  - Storefront Theater, 1983
  - Stouffer's
  - Strand Theater - SEE ALSO American Film Theater
  - Street, Lori, 1983
  - Street Theater, 1986-1991
  - Street Theatre Entertainment in Pittsburgh, 1988
  - Stuart Pimsler Dance and Theater, 1990
  - Studio of the Theatre, The - SEE Laboratory Theatre
  - Summer Players of Pleasant Hills, 1975
  - Summer theatre, 1976-1986
  - Suranovich, George, 1990
  - Sweet Adelines, Inc., 1979
  - Synod Hall, 1977
- T
  - Talent from Pittsburgh, 1954-1964
  - Tatar, Ben, 1978
  - Taylor Allderdice High School, 1981-1982
  - Taylor, Greg, 1989
  - Taylor, Mark, 1990
  - Tebelak, John-Michael, 1971-1978
  - Temeles, Sam, 1989
  - Templeton, Fay, 1934-1981
  - Terry, Ellen, 1907-1947
  - Theatre at Seven Springs
  - Theatre Comique - SEE Third Street Theatre
  - Theatre in the Square, 1983-1987
  - Theatre Limited
  - Theatre on the Ridge - SEE Holiday Inn - Irwin
  - Theatre North, 1979
  - Theater on Wheels, 1984
  - Theatre Pittsburgh, 1984
  - Theater Sports - SEE ALSO Rosebud, 1991-1993
  - Theatre Unlimited
  - Theatre Urge - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1981-1982
  - Theatre Wagon, 1962
  - Theatre Yes! - SEE ALSO Audience Surveys, 1975-1976
  - Theatres - Pittsburgh History, 1901-1989
  - Theatreworkers Project, 1986
  - Theatrical Assistance Agency of Pittsburgh, 1975
  - Theodore L. Hazlett Theater - SEE Hazlett Theatre
  - Thespis Summer Theatre Camp, 1975
  - Thiel College, 1977-1983
  - Third Street Theatre
  - Thirty-Seventh street players, 1983
  - This Week in Pittsburgh, 1932-1933
  - Thomas, Olive, 2003-2004
  - Thomas, Thom, 1984-1990
  - Thompson, Anthony, 1990
  - Thompson, Lauren, 1981-1990
  - Thornburg Players, 1981
  - Three Quarters Below the Street
  - Three Rivers Arts Festival, 1961-1996
  - Three Rivers Film Festival - SEE ALSO Festivals, celebrations, pageants, etc., 1990-1991
  - Throughline Theatre Company, 2012-current
  - Tickets
  - Timespace, 1994-1997
  - Tix Booth - SEE ALSO Pittsburgh Allegheny County Cultural Alliance, 1984-1985
  - Today Show in Pittsburgh, 1987
  - Toomey, Regis, 1961
  - Totally Bard Theatre, 1994
  - Totem Pole Playhouse, 1987
  - Towne & Country Players, 1946-1956
  - Toy, Camben, 1990-1992
  - Travelling Troupe, 1983-1984
  - Trimbles Varieties
  - Trinity Square Repertory Company
  - Tri-Rivers Clowns - SEE Clowns
  - Turner, William, 1980
  - Turrentine, Stanley
  - Turtle Creek Area Play Guild, 1979-1981
  - Twentieth Century Club, 1931-1951
  - TWD Productions, 1994
  - Twenty-five Market Square, 1980
  - Twin Coaches, 1977
  - Twin Rose Productions - SEE Holiday Inn - Irwin
- U
  - Ujima Theatre, 1976
  - Ultimate Soap Opera Festival, 1990
  - Undercroft Opera, 2009-current
  - Underground Railroad Theater, 1990
  - Underwood, Blair, 1989
  - Underwood Dance Theatre
  - Unicorn Productions, 1982-1985
  - Union Cafe, 1984
  - United States Bicentennial 1976 (in Pennsylvania) - SEE ALSO Brockett, Don
  - University of Pittsburgh - Cap and Gown Club
  - University of Pittsburgh theatre (not Theatre Arts Department), 1976-1996
  - University of Pittsburgh - Greensburg Campus, 1982
  - University of Pittsburgh - Johnstown Campus
  - Unseam'd Shakespeare Company, 2005
  - Upper St. Clair Community Playhouse - SEE ALSO Upper St. Clair Players
  - Upper St. Clair Players - SEE ALSO Upper St. Clair Community Playhouse, 1975-1977
- V
  - Valley Theatre Co., 1989
  - Valley Players of Ligonier, Inc., 1981-current
  - Vanguard Theatre, 1964-1972
  - Variety Club's Tent No.1, 1982
  - Vaux, Lyn, 1990
  - Venberg, Lorraine, 1987-1990
  - Verlander, Tara, 1977
  - Victoria Theatre - SEE ALSO Aldine Theatre, Sam S. Schubert Theatre, 1917
  - Village Playhouse, 1990
  - Vinton, Bobby, 1977-1989
  - Vogue Terrace Playhouse
- W
  - Wadsworth, Don, 1990
  - Wagon Wheel Playhouse, 1951-1952
  - Walt Harper's Attic - SEE ALSO Harper's and Caplan, Betty, 1975
  - Warhol, Andy, 1975-1989
  - Warner Center - SEE ALSO Davis, Harry and Warner Theater, 1985-1986
  - Warner Theater - SEE ALSO Warner Center, 1983
  - Warren, Bob - SEE ALSO Bob Warren Productions, 1980
  - Washington and Jefferson College Center Stage Players, 1983-2007
  - Washington Community Theater, 1979-1983
  - Washington Theatre, 2009
  - Way Off Broadway - SEE ALSO Gina's Restaurant, 1976
  - Waynesburg College, 1975
  - Weaver, Fritz, 1977-1983
  - Webster Hall, 1934
  - Weiland Theatres, 1920
    Scope and Contents
    Program for both the Stand Theatre in Knoxville and the Rialto Theatre in Mt. Oliver.
  - We Quit Our Day Jobs Theater Co., 1997
  - We're Entertainment, Inc. - SEE ALSO Fine Line Cultural Center, 1983
  - West Hills Community Theatre, 1978-1982
  - Westminster College, 1981-1991
  - Westmoreland County Community College, 1991
  - Wexford Community Theatre, 1980-1985
  - White's New Theatre, 1910
  - Wick's Opera House, 1914
  - Widdoes, James, 1982
  - Wiegand, Roy, 1990
  - Wilde, Pat, 1951-1990
  - Wilkinsburg Art Council Theatre, 1987
  - Wilkinsburg Playshop, 1980
  - William Penn Hotel, 1934
  - Wilson, August, 1981-current
  - Winks, Michael, 1989
  - Wisniski, Ron, 1981-1990
  - Wolken, Jonathan, 1990
  - Wolpert, Stuart, 1987
  - Women's Clubs, 1936-1964
  - Word of Mouth Theatre, 1984
  - WQED, 1975-1990
  - WRS Motion Pictures and Film Laboratory, 1991-2001
  - WTAE
- Y
  - Yates, Dolores, 1989
  - Y Civic Playhouse - SEE Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association
  - Y Triangle Players - SEE Young Men's Christian Association
  - Yiddish theatre
  - Yorkin, Bud, 1990
  - Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association, 1928-1974
  - Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association - Irene Kaufmann Centers - SEE Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1931-1952
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Coraopolis, 1948
  - Young Women's Christian Association, 1945-1982
  - Yuhas, Robert, 1989
- Z
  - Zito and Bean - SEE ALSO Portfolio and Comedy Clubs, 1982
  - Zoppe Circus Europa, 1987-1989